This is English Hello, we
Вот это английский Здравствуйте
continue to revive the English section
продолжаем оживлять рубрику английский
based on films and today we have another
по фильмам и Сегодня у нас ещё один
villain Cannibal Lecturer, as you
злодей Каннибал Лектор у лектора как
know, the lecturer has a very high intellect, so the
известно очень высокий интеллект поэтому
words he uses will be extremely
слова которые он использует будут крайне
interesting and complex. But those that
интересными сложными Но те которые
make him sound exactly like a
заставляют его звучать именно так как
brilliant
гениального
villain are not that I wanted you to
злодея не то чтобы я хотел чтобы вы
talk like brilliant villains, but
разговаривали гениальные злодеи но тем
nevertheless, it sounds very beautiful when a
не менее это звучит очень красиво когда
person has a large vocabulary when
у человека большой словарный запас когда
he uses more complex, more
он использует более сложное более
beautiful words, expressions. It is always
красивые слова выражения Это всегда
pleasant to listen to and always creates a
приятно слушать и всегда создаёт
feeling that a person has intelligence. This is what
ощущение наличия у человека интеллекта
I would also like for you. I
Вот этого я для вас бы хотел также
remind you that for this lesson, as well as for
Напоминаю что к этому уроку как и ко
all the others, there are additional
всем остальным есть дополнительные
materials at the link in the description of this
материалы по ссылке в описании к этому
video, there will be exercises that I have
видео там будут упражнения которые я
compiled, fill in the blanks, complete
составил заполнить пропуски дополнить
sentences, and so on, work with
предложения и так далее работа с
vocabulary so that it
лексикой для того чтобы она у вас
remains in your head for a long time, of course,
осталась в голове на совсем конечно же
cards for this issue with the most
карточки к этому выпуску с самыми
difficult words that you can
сложными словами которые вы можете
get on your phone with voice acting and
получить на телефоне с озвучкой с
pictures, everything as it should be, at the link in the
картинками всё как положено по ссылке в
description, download and I will study so that
описании скачивайте и позанимаюсь чтобы
all the material studied is fixed
весь изученный материал закрепился у вас
in your head  reinforced concrete Well, now
в голове железобетонно Ну а теперь
let's
Давайте
get started I turned on this scene a little bit in advance
приступим я чуть-чуть заранее эту сцену
Where she will still go to
Включил там где она ещ будет заходить на
her There will be these criminals watching
неё там Будут смотреть эти преступники
So I hope you are not in a
Так что я надеюсь вы никуда не
hurry today
торопитесь сегодня
[music]
[музыка]
My
My
Name
Name
with ials [
with ials
music]
[музыка]
Well, here she is greeted in prison
Ну вот её приветствуют в тюрьме
the prisoner
заключённый
says I never know what to do with
говорит Я никогда не знаю что делать с
swearing Especially with such in my analysis
матами Особенно с такими в моих разбора
so let's I will give the floor to
поэтому Давайте Я предоставлю слово
your imagination and dictionary Google it
вашему воображению и словарю Погугли
yourself
сами
but SM is to smell the smell SM I can smell
но SM - это учуять запах SM я могу чуять
Yes, to
Да
sniff like
нюхать типа
[music]
[музыка]
from here So let's start a dialogue
отсюда Так давайте к диалогу
right away everything is like in an English club Yes, there are
сразу тут всё как в английском клубе Да
no new words
никаких новых слов нет
while she is speaking Can I talk to
пока она говорит Могу ли я поговорить с
you that is, such a very polite
вами то есть такая самая вежливая
form one
форма одна
of frh like one of his isn't it
из из фрх типа одна из его не так ли
Can I see your IDs
Могу ли я увидеть ваши удостоверения
Your documents cral Let's write down
Ваши документы cral Давайте запишем
Lecturer is a doctor a learned man Therefore,
Лектор доктор человек учёный Поэтому у
he will have the bulk of interesting
него будет основная масса интересных
words today by the way, they immediately show us all sorts of
слов сегодня вот кстати нам сразу всякие
IDs
ксивы показывают
Rovka you see how politely and he tells her
Ровки видите как вежливо и он ей говорит
and such  intelligentsia guys
и такие интеллигенты ребята
definitely of
определённо
course certain some specific of
конечно определённый какой-то конкретный
course
конечно
definitely Well and when she takes out the
определённо Ну и когда она достаёт
documents He
документы Он ей
tells her closer please too We see
говорит ближе пожалуйста тоже Мы видим
here how it happens
здесь как это происходит
I
I
Yes mayen closer please closer that
Yes
expires in One We not FBI are you I
that expires in One We not FBI are you
'm Still in
I'm Still in
Training Ja craw Train
Training Ja craw
Yes
Train Yes
Student Here Learn you May you can fori
Student Here Learn you May you can fori
- this is when the expiration date expires
- это когда срок годности заканчивается
on a product for example some or as
на продукте например каком-то или как у
we have
нас
here piecework
здесь сдельно
We will delete this about the term so that it does not
Мы удалим это о сроке чтобы оно не
interfere with you learning later expire here we
мешало потом вам учить expire вот мы
see on the table expired istk
видим табличке expired истк срок
expiration date that is, everything is no longer relevant
годности то есть уже всё не актуально
expire on the card Yes we have expires
expire на карточке Да у нас вот expires
such and such a date expire expire
такого-то там числа expire истекать
expir in this yes This document expir
expir in это да Этот документ expir
expires expiration date expires in
истекает срок годности заканчивается in
One in a week in English in one
One через неделю по-английски в од
week F
неделю F
you are not real FBI
ты не настоящий FBI
by the way
кстати
bu in my opinion Federal Bureau of
bu помоему Федеральное бюро
Investigation F
расследований F
so isn't it so
поэтому не так
I am still in training Yes I am still
ли я ВС ещ в тренировки Да ВС ещ
studying at the Academy
учусь в Академии
Ja Crawford Train ะด Crawford sent
Ja Crawford Train д Crawford послал
Train to train Train Train to
Train тренироваться Train Train
train that's what she said
тренироваться вот как она и сказала
still in Training I'm still in training
still in Training Я всё ещё в тренировки
Ja Crawford Train a Train is someone who
Ja Crawford Train а Train - это тот кто
trains Yes, someone who is still studying is the same as
тренируется Да тот кто ещё обучается
employ hire
тоже самое что employ нанимать на работу
emplo - This is an employee This is and at the end
emplo - Это работник Вот это и в конце
it means that this is the person who does this
это обозначает что это человек который
Train to train Train
вот это делает Train тренироваться Train
the one who trains employer employee
тот кто тренируется employer employee
appoint appointee the one who was
appoint назначать appointee тот кого
appointed nominate nominee
назначили nominate номинировать nominee
nominees By the way, it is often
номинанты Кстати часто довольно
used Escape is to
используется Escape - это откуда-то
get out of somewhere or from prison, for example, to
выбираться или из тюрьмы например
escape Escape the one who escaped Well, in general, there
сбегать Escape тот кто сбежал Ну в общем
is such a joke with these and at the end
есть такой прикол с вот этими и в конце
Ja Crawford sent Train DK Crawford sent
Ja Crawford sent Train ДК крофорд послал
you a student to
ти ученика ко
me I am a
мне Я
student I am here to learn from you
ученица Я здесь чтобы учиться от вас у
you have a cool accent it is not so unusual
вас прикольный акцент неста такой необыч
Maybe you can
Может быть вы можете
decide for yourself Maybe you
решить за вас самих Может быть вы сами
can decide for yourself let's also write decide for By
сможете решить давайте тоже запишем
the way, he also
decide for Он кстати так тоже нам
suggests that we decide for ourselves decide to make an
предлагает решить за себя сам решить
independent decision we will
принять самостоятельное решение мы
write it down more briefly decide for ourselves May
запишем покороче решить самому
Maybe you can decide for yourself
May Может быть вы можете сами решить
not means yes or no
not значит да или нет либо
or am I qualified
либо квалифицирована ли я
enough to do this
достаточно чтобы делать это ещ
again maybe you can decide for yourself as if it were true  is it
раз может вы сами решите как бы правда
or
это или
not that I am
нет что я
qualified enough to do
квалифицирована достаточно чтобы делать
this
это
so of course it sounds like a tongue twister
так конечно как скороговорка звучит
well that's why it's cool to break it all down in advance
ну-ка поэтому и классно заранее так всё
with subtitles and an explanation
разобрать с субтитрами и с пояснением
because then it becomes
потому что потом становится
clear It's
понятно Это
pretty it's slippery if this
довольно это скользко если бы это
conversation was about the street and the weather
разговор был про улицу и про погоду
for example then it would be just slippery
например то это было бы просто скользко
wet slippery but
влажно скользкий но у нас
here it's pretty slippery from you that
здесь это довольно скользко от вас то
is it's pretty tricky tricky ST aen ST
есть это довольно хитро хитро ST аен ST
how you suck up to me
как Вы ко мне подлизывается
[music]
[музыка]
Please sit down
Присаживайтесь пожалуйста
rather slippery you AG daring pleas Now Tell What Say you mulle in the Next He you He
rather slippery you AG
Said can smell
you He Said can smell
So literally now then here's such an
Итак дословно сейчас тогда вот такое вот
introductory word So tell me
вводное слово Итак расскажите мне
what they told You he explains specifically
что сказали Вам он поясняет специально
mple in the plural mixes in the
mple во множественном числе миксы in the
Next in the next cell Cell -
Next в следующей камере Cell - это в
depending on the context this is either a cell of
зависимости от контекста либо ячейка
some kind for example in a table or if we are
какая-то например в таблице либо если мы
talking about a prison then this is definitely a
говорим про тюрьму то это однозначно
prison cell but we will write Cell as a
камера тюремная но мы запишем Cell как
cell Let's open the pictures and the
клетка Давайте откроем картинки и в
pictures usually show how it is
картинках как правило показывается то
used most often By the way  a
как чаще всего используется Вот кстати
cell that is alive and is in the body
клетка та которая живая и в организме
too Cell a cell although it does not
находится тоже Cell клетка хотя она не
look square Yes Does not look like a
выглядит квадратной Да Не похожа на
cell Cell Let's write N Excell Yes a
клетку Cell Давайте напишем N Excell Да
cell in the Excel program it will
клетка в программе Excel она будет Вот
look like this Cell and a prison Cell is a
так выглядеть Cell а тюремная Cell - это
prison cell
камера тюремная
Well, apparently he calls it in the
Ну вот он видимо его во множественном
plural maybe he has
числе называет может быть у него
some kind of
какие-то там размножение
personality reproduction that's why
личности поэтому
they are
они
numerous in the neighboring
многочисленны соседней
cell of course there
камере животных конечно
will be animals but here it is clear that this is about a
будет но у нас здесь понятно что это про
person Here we come across cats and
человека Вот коты у нас попадаются и
snakes and the word itself it just hisses
змеи и само слово оно как раз так и
he hissed at
шипит он шипел на
you and what did he
тебя а что же он
say is clear Well,
сказал понятно
in general I see Yes
Ну вот вообще я вижу Да
but
но
I myself can't Well or I personally can't here
я сам не могу Ну или Я лично не могу вот
in Russian what for some reason are we saying I
по-русски что же зачем-то говорим Я
personally could just say I can't
лично можно было просто сказать я не
but this carries
могу но это несёт
a certain connotation with it I personally can't
определённый оттенок за собой Я лично не
eat someone can but I personally can't so
могу есть кто-то может а я лично нет так
here I personally can't I can't
тут я вот не могу лично я не могу
you use Skin Cream Did you do All That
you use Skin
From the
That From the
you use AV Skin Cream SK skin
вы пользуетесь AV Skin Cream SK кожа
cream well that is lotion for skin or cream
крем ну то есть лосьон для кожи или крем
for skin What do we
для кожи Как мы
call Well that is you use
называем Ну то есть вы пользуетесь
such and such  such and such
таким-то таким-то
SK skin cream
SK кремом для кожи
in English you can say about clothes
по-английски можно сказать и про одежду
and about perfume you can wear both with the
и про духи носить можно и то и то со
word But not
словом Но не
today You
сегодня Вы
did uh
сделали э
listen to this word because yes Here I
слушаем это слово потому что да Вот я
feel that I don't want to pronounce this W here
чувствую что мне не хочется эту W здесь
but I wasn't sure how it would be
произносить но я не был уверен как будет
in
в
transcription that is to say it's not here at all well
транскрипции то есть вообще её здесь
in British as always there is
нет ну в британском как всегда там
some letter as if another one is
какая-то буква как буд таки ещё одна
heard
слышна
as a drawing to draw I was always
как рисунок рисовать меня вообще всегда
more attracted to the
больше привлекало
word but still a
слово но вс-таки сло
certain
определённый
shade pencil it's such a less
оттенок карандашное это такой менее
finished less complex drawing But
законченный менее сложный рисунок А вот
Painting if we enter then here it will be a
Painting если мы введём то тут будет
picture it's usually with paints
прямо картина это как правило с красками
on canvas This is Painting drawing it's
на холсте Вот это Painting drawing он
such a little simpler after all that's
такой немножечко попроще всё-таки
why the words are
поэтому слова
different it's you who made all these drawings
разные это вы сделали все эти рисунки
drawings you can see not paintings but drawings exactly
рисунки види не картины а рисунки именно
visible sdi there is this if you look at beldi
видна сди есть это если смотреть бельди
All you
All
know
знаете
floren VSeti
флорен ВСети
de iz
де из
pam VS
пам ВС
remember
помните
memory this is what I
память это то что я
have instead of a view the
имею вместо вида
word view too Let's look at the
слово вид тоже Давайте посмотрим
pictures
картинки
VI this is what we see out the window well or
VI это то что мы видим в окошко ну или
when we are in nature
когда находимся на приро
what I
то что у меня
have instead of a
есть вместо
view  look how she raids him with
вида смотрите как она его облава ет прям
words Well,
словами Ну чтож
maybe you would like to
возможно вас было бы
specifically say it VI - This is a
желание специально его говорит VI - Это
view but here it is a look Yes, your
вид но здесь это взгляд Да ваш
view of this questionnaire - This is a
взгляд на этот опросник - Это
question questionnaire that is, a questionnaire where there are
вопрос опросник то есть анкета там где
many questions Sir In general, she
много вопросов Sir В общем она его
is trying to envelop him with the most beautiful words somehow
самыми красивыми словами пытается как-то
Land to lend to lend from
окутать Land одалживать давать в долг у
us L US your View Lend us your
нас L US your View Одолжите нам ваш
view your point of view and - This is a questionnaire
взгляд вашу точку зрения и - Это анкета
Pay attention to the spelling of this
Обратите внимание на написание этого
word it is quite difficult the word itself
слова оно довольно сложное само слово
try to
ещё попробуй
write a more difficult task let's
напиши задача посложнее давайте
listen to
послушаем
it questionnaire questionnaire and so on
его анкета вопросник и так далее
You
Ты же так хорошо
did it so well you did it well that is, you
справлялась ты делала хорошо то есть у
succeeded in everything you
тебя всё получалось
this
ты вот это
word it has such a different
слово оно имеет настолько разное
meaning that I am interested even in understanding
значение что мне интересно даже разбра
why it is so
почему так
And if we enter in the picture there will
И если мы введем в картинке там
definitely be exactly the judicial all sorts of
по-любому будет именно судейская всякая
Theme yes At the same time, when we talk about
Тема да При этом когда мы говорим про
relationships, it is
отношения
like courting here we entered That
то это как бы ухаживать вот мы ввели То
is, if it is used as a verb, then it is to settle
есть если это как глагол использовать то
her in to court to ride in a
это её обживать ухаживать катать на
car All this I do
машине Всё вот это вот
n't know how it ended up there to seduce
не знаю как это там оказалось соблазнять
Yes  okay, let's not dig too far,
Да ладно не будем сильно далеко копать
but the word comes from here,
но отсюда же идёт
and already If there, then here it is read
причём уже Если там то тут читается
politeness, courtesy, etiquette.
вежливость обходительность этикет Вот
This already has to do with
это уже имеет отношение именно к
courtship if there is C politeness, courtesy,
ухаживания если есть C вежливость
then a polite, polite person, once again,
то обходительный вежливый человек ещё
polite, polite, courteous, all the
учтивый вежливый обходительный все
works, politeness, courtesy. Let's write them both down.
дела вежливость учтивость Давайте оба их
C politeness, courtesy and
запишем C вежливость учтивость и
polite, and he
вежливый вот и он ей
says to her, you were like this
говорит вы были такой
[music]
[музыка]
polite - this is accepting, that is, such
учтиво - это принимающий то есть такой
that could
которая могла
accept and were
принимать и были
receptive to politeness, courtesy.
восприимчивый к учтиво обходительность
That is, he says, we are with you. Yes,
То есть он говорит мы же с вами
you were
Да вы были
considerate and you accepted
учти и вы принимали
politeness. You established
учтивость Вы установили
trust in what way, this
Доверие каким способом
unpleasant from which the little ones
сю неприятный от которого чки
blush with this embarrassment to the
краснеют этой смущай
truth, that is, as if we were with you. Yes, we
правде то есть как бы мы с вами Да
established
установили
trust. There is, she did not lie about what I
довери есть она не соврала о том что ми
told her. Let's do it
сказал вы давайте так
even a psychiatrist. I think he knows this
даже психиатр по-моему он знает этот
term. This is exactly when two people
термин это как раз когда два человека
or a patient and, for example, a
или пациент и например
psychiatrist do it so that they have This is
психиатр делают так что у них возникает
trust between each other. It is
Вот это доверие друг Между другом оно
used specifically with the
именно используется со
word. You established
словом Вы установили
trust with the help of this unpleasant truth.
Доверие с помощью этой неприятной правд
promise
промиса
and now this is
а теперь
- this is ham hand this is a person who has
это - это ветчина рука это вот человек у
ham instead of hands that is
которого вместо рук ветчина то есть
Clumsy here we see in all the pictures
Неуклюжий вот мы видим на всех картинках
someone doing something clumsy And this
кто-то делает что-то неуклюжее И вот эта
phrase is played out in the picture now I'll
фраза обыгрывается в картинке сечас
open it surgeons with a vein instead of hands
открою хирурги с веной вме рук
let's also write down
давайте тоже запишем
Clumsy knucklehead offers us a quizlet
Неуклюжий рукожоп нам предлагает квизлет
Well, let's write it down for a good mood
Ну давайте для хорошего настроения
knucklehead is written a little differently than it is
рукожоп пишется немножко не так как
pronounced as if a couple of
произносится как будто не хватает пары
letters are missing but
букв но тем не
nevertheless We also know such things in Russian
менее Мы по-русски тоже знаем такие
on two braids that they ride
штуки на двух косах на которых катаются
and now this is some kind of
а теперь это какая-то
Clumsy this is a transition Apparently they are
Неуклюжая это переход Видимо они
called because you can
называются потому что на них можно
quickly move somewhere on them move
быстро куда-то переходить передвигаться
But
Но
in general here is a
вообще вот
transition he moved on to another
переход он перешёл к другой
topic transition to move from one to
теме переход переходить от одного к
another pere
другому пере
your
ваш
questionnaire so listened to
опросник так переслушал
F and to had established trust the embar
F and to had established trust the embar
tru Now This he seg it won do
tru Now This hed
Asking you to Look at You will won Yeah Jack cwf
do Asking you to Look at You will won
must be very bought If he
Yeah Jack cwf must be very buyed If he
recruiting  From the Student Body bu
recruiting From the Student Body bu
hunting that buff let's
hunting that buff
continue like this won't work literally it won't do it there won't work
продолжим так не пойдёт дословно это не
It's just a speech But it's a really awesome
Сто это говор Но это и правда офигенная
phrase It won't work Let's
фраза Так не пойдет Давайте на этот раз
look at a couple of examples from
посмотрим пару примеров из
movies this time as we see We often
фильмов как мы видим Часто у нас
come across won't do anything good but
попадается не сделает ничего хорошего но
we came across this phrase regardless
у нас эта фраза встретилась независи
so don't
так не
sweat I just
пот Я всего лишь
ask you to look at
прошу посмотреть на
this Either you will yes or you will look
это Либо вы будете да либо Вы посмотрите
Either you
Либо вы
must be very busy really
должен быть очень занятой действительно
really probably very busy
на самом деле наверно очень занят
if he Bert help Yes hires as we
если он Берт помощь Да нанимает как мы
also say
тоже говорим
recruit from students Well here
рекрутировать из студентско Ну ба здесь
as a corps rather Yes here has nothing to do with the
как корпус скорее Да тут ничего общего с
body for example corporate
телом не имеет вот к примеру corporate
Body corporate Well not a body yes but a branch
Body корпоративное Ну не тело да а ветвь
as if a department or that's exactly it
как бы отделение или вот именно это
part of some
часть какой-то
organization corporate as if an organ
организации корпоративный как бы орган
Yes well or a corporate
Да ну или корпоративное
department is
отделение
responsible for managing the
ответственно за то чтобы управлять
assets of the organization organization
активами of the organization организации
Well in general in such a spirit Body therefore don't
Ну в общем в таком духе Body поэтому не
think that here we are talking about anything bodies
думайте что тут ни про чё тела речь не
if he hires help froment from
идёт если он нанимает помощь froment от
students Yes from the student corps is
студентов Да из студентско корпуса
busy hunting busy hunting Well or  hunting
занят охотой busy hunting Ну или охотясь
that New One for this New One brand new
that New One за этим New One новеньким
Buffalo Bell named Buffalo Bill
Buffalo Bell по имени Buffalo Bill
Buffalo Bell American sold American
Buffalo Bell American sold американский
soldier in general there is such a character in Well
солдат в общем есть такой персонаж в Ну
or even a real living person but he is
или даже настоящий живой человек но он
already like a household name this Buffalo Bell
уже как нарицательное этот Buffalo Bell
American sold American soldier Bon
American sold американский солдат Bon
hunter buffalo hunter And Show
hunter охотник на бизонов And Show
names well I said it right without
имен ну-ка Правильно я сказал безо
one of the most
один из самых
famous also good to know well
известных тоже хорошо знать хорошо
recognizable Old American old
узнаваемых Old американского старого
West Well in short a cowboy such yes
Запада Ну короче ковбой такой да
stereotypical buff Bell and a soldier he is a
стереотипный buff Bell и солдат он и
hunter and who
охотник и кто
wants a new this But this is the nickname
хочешь нового этого Но это прозвище
that they called the new maniac some kind of
которым назвали нового маньяка какого-то
he was called buff
его назвали buff
naughty Boy he is what
непослушный Мальчишка он есть какой
Naughty
Непослушный
boy bad naughty
мальчик плохой непослушный
capricious what a capricious boy
капризный какой же капризный мальчик
naughty do you know
непослушный вы знаете
why he is called that
почему его так называ
Tell me
Расскажите мне
please they won't say yes the newspapers don't
пожалуйста не скажут да газеты не
say it it
говорят
all started like a Bad
этого началось это всё как Плохая
joke this is what the
шутка это так называется
department is called - this is the murder department where they investigate the
отдел - это убийств отдел где расследуют
murder homicide department Let's
убийство убойный отдел
write down in principle this is what they call it when a
Запишем в принципе так называют когда
murder just happened some kind of
просто произошло убийство какое-то
deprivation of a person's life so in principle they
лишение человека жизни так в принципе и
say and in films too often  cops
говорят и в фильмах тоже часто копы
When they arrive at the scene they also kill
Когда приезжают на место они тоже уби
it's
это
skin but we have a verb Yes what to do it's to
кожа но у нас глагол Да что делать это
remove the skin That is how it is there is a
снимать кожу То
word some even
есть как это есть слово какое-то даже
fresh in my opinion
свеже по-моему
it's such a
это такое
dismissive dismissive
пренебрежительно пренебрежительный
verb denoting some kind of
глагол обозначающий какие-то
wine but if we look at this word with the
ви но если мы посмотрим на это слово
innocent eyes of a baby we will see
невинными глазами младенца то мы увидим
that it means hump bump hunch
что это обозначает горб бугор горбится
Let's watch pictures of humps like this Of course that's
Давайте тя картинки горбов смотреть
why if this is
такое Конечно вот поэтому если в этом
just the meaning of the
просто значение
word blue So here Let's listen again
слова блю Так что вот Давайте пере
hes
hes
[music]
[музыка]
and why do you think before that he
а почему вы думаете вот он до этого
simply said in one word
просто одним словом
something like that he dumped them removed the
сказал чтото такое что он свал их снимал
skin And here he literally laid out this
кожу А здесь он буквально разложил эту
phrase with and
фразу с
Why do you
и А почему вы
think he removes them
думаете он убирает их
[music]
[музыка]
skin this
кожу это
excitement is so exciting hence the
волнение тако волнующее отсюда
word
слово
platoon the word but on
взвод слово но на
mi insight intelligence sharpness of
ми проницательность сообразительность
mind amaze me with your
ума поразите меня своей
insight
проницательностью
said to show
сказал проявить
ingenuity legal insight That
смекалку юридическая проницательность То
is to say in what area
есть можно сказать в какой области
first
сначала
intuition e yes
чуйка е да
grip won her the elections that is
хватка выиграла ей выборы то есть
thanks to this she
благодаря этому она
won
победила
[music]
[музыка]
excited let's write it down It
взволновало запишем оно Обязательно
should definitely end up in our lexicon even though
должно оказаться в нашем лексиконе хоть
Hannibal is a maniac at the same time You see
Ганнибал и маньяк в то же время Видите
what a good vocabulary he has
какой у него хороший словарный запас
[music] there is a
[музыка]
word it is used more often and here it is a
есть слово оно чаще используется а здесь
verb what to do
она глагол что делать
excite
взволновать
excited gets high from it Let's
взволнован кайфует от этого Давайте
write it down Although I think it is a fairly
запишем Хотя я думаю довольно
common word you have come across it somewhere Yes, you have definitely come across it
распространённое слово вы его где-нибудь
so we
Да по-любому встречали поэтому мы
will do it like this
сделаем вот
cart
так воз
G And in general, I just
Г И вообще в общем слова просто
write down words as words and that's it I started
записываю как слова и вс я так стал сам
doing it myself when I learn other foreign
делать когда учу другие иностранные
languages โโand it's somehow better for me to go to bed
языки и это как-то мне лучше ложиться
therefore there are fewer hassles in general as a
поэтому и меньше заморочек вообще в
result it's
итоге это
excited serial
взволнован серийных
RTV didn't
РТВ так не
do that You ate
делал Вы ели
yours there are in the past
ваших есть в прошедшем
tense send
времени
in general Let's pass
отправлять в общем Давайте передавайте
me your this
мне свой этот
envelope you Send it through
конверт вы Пошлите это сквозь
now Come on pass it on you see he speaks
сечас Давай передавай видите он говорит
very
очень
directively he told her at the beginning sit down now he
директивно он ей в начале сказал садись
tells her pass it on That is,
сейчас он говорит ей передавай То есть
he completely controls the situation in
он полностью контролирует ситуацию в
which he is Although he is behind bars
которой он находится Хотя он за решёткой
now
сейчас
so again
так ещё раз
[music]
[музыка]
AG  you Think can
AG you Think can
BL no
BL no
you
вы
think I think this
думаете я думаю тут имеет отношение это
word has to do with the word section because
слово к слову раздел секция потому что
it is to
это
divide by the way he
разделять кстати он
says Yes he tells us the dictionary
говорит Да он говори словар нам
Dat dissect dissect open that
Дат рассекать препарировать вскрывать то
is
есть
say do you think you can me like a
говори вы думаете вы сможете меня как
frog Yes open look
лягушку Да вскрыть посмотреть
it is blunt that is Let's for example
это тупой то есть Давайте например
introduce
введём
BL blunt knife anu For example yes a knife
BL тупой нож ану Вот например да нож
which is a table knife which is specifically
который столовый который конкретно
used When you eat BL let
используется Когда вы едите BL давайте
's even open a page here is a knife
мы даже откроем страничку вот ножик
called so-and-so
называется так-то так-то
blain blunt
blain тупой
and this is a
и это
spot without spots
пятно без пятен
on which spots do not
на которой пятна не
appear e usually write
появляются е обычно пишут
steel it doesn't matter we are interested in the
сталь неважно нас интересует
word do you think you can me
слово вы думаете вы меня сможете
cut
разрезать
examine with a blunt little instrument
исследовать тупым маленьким инструменти
your
ком вашим
I thought that your
Я думала что ваши
knowledge is ambitious
знания амбициозная
know what you look like to me who
знаете как вы выглядите для меня на кого
you look like
вы похожи
and your cheap
и вашими дешёвыми тиночка
country bumpkin they
деревенщина они с нами
treated us like booths we
обращались как будки мы
were offered translation by country
были предлагается перевод деревенскими
suckers but
лохами но
in English a bunch of country bumpkins well here is the
по-английски скопище деревенщин а ну вот
word R this is rural maybe from it
слово R это сельский возможно от него
comes rural country bumpkin and so on  then
идёт сельский деревенский и так далее
country bumpkins Let's
деревенщины Давайте
write down
запишем
country bumpkin You look like a
деревенщина Ты выглядишь как
country bumpkin Look like to me with your
деревенщина Look like to me with your
Good and your Shoes you look like a
Good and your Shoes you look like
well scrubbed hing with Little tast Good Nutrition giv
a a well scrubbed hing with Little
you Some length of
tast Good Nutrition giv you Some length
Bone But You're not More than One
of Bone But You're not More than One
Generation From Poor TR are you AG
Generation From Poor TR are you AG
starling and that Accent you tried so
starling and that Accent you tried so
desperately to SH Pure West Virginia What is
desperately to SH Pure West virginia
your you look like a r
your you look like a r
[music]
[музыка]
good SC - this is ัะบัะตะฟะธ from ััะตะบะฐัั (scrape) That
хорошо SC - это скрести от скре бать То
is, well cleaned and washed let's
есть хорошо очищенная да вымытая давайте
write down or ัะบัััั (rub) Well, how in
запишем или скрести тереть Ну вот как в
this context well
этом контексте хорошо
washed (pour) that's what I like to say in Russian
вымытая лить вот мне нравится по-русски
although this word is not
так говорить хотя это слово не то что
often used But ัะฐัะปะธั - is to
часто использовалось Но хаслить - это
do some
заниматься какими-то
things very actively intensively that is,
делами очень активно интенсивно то есть
to try to stir up something to
пытаться что-то намутить
do well
сделать хорошо
washed active trying to achieve something
вымытая деятельная пытающиеся чего-то
country bumpkin with little taste
деревенщина с маленьким вкусом
tasteless from a cannibal lecturer to hear
безвкусно от каннибала лектора слышать
when they talk about your taste here you can
когда говорят про твой вкус тут можно и
understand it literally of course
буквально понять конечно
[music]
[музыка]
good
хорошее
nutrition  gave
питание дало
you some
тебе некоторую длину
bone length that is you ate well
костей то есть ты хорошо питалась
so your bones
поэтому кости у тебя
grew gave
выросли дало
those some bone length
те кое-какую длину кости
but you are no
но ты не
more than one
более чем на одно
generation away from Poor white trash Well that's what they
поколение от Бедного белого мусора Ну
call poor white people in
так называют бедных белых людей в
English in America in
английском языке в Америке в
particular but you are no more than
частности но ты ушла не больше чем на
one
одно
[music]
[музыка]
generation away from poor Poor people usually still
поколение бедных Бедняков как правило ещ
live in the south that's what they call American Is
жите юга так называют американского
n't that the
Не так
AKN that you
акн который ты
tried so
Пыталась так
desperately to hide Let's write down the
отчаянно скрыть Давайте запишем
word Desperate I wrote it wrong or something No that's right
слово Отчаянный не так написал что ли
Desperate
Нет так Отчаянный
that you tried so desperately then SH
который ты Пыталась так отчаянно то SH
most often I come across in the context of shed to
чаще всего я встречаю в контексте shed
shed light SH more precisely even Usually they
пролить свет SH точнее даже Обычно
say here SH Light SH Light on to shed
говорят вот SH Light SH Light on пролить
light on something that's exactly how it
на что-то свет вот мне именно так
comes across to me Could you shed some light
попадается Не могли бы вы пролить свет
on this problem to illuminate it But in general You
на эту проблему осветить её Но вообще
see a barn shed I don't know why
Вот видите сарай навес Я не знаю почему
and to spill and to pour and a barn shed too
и проливать и лить и сарай навес тоже
how it happened in the language only God
как так произошло в языке одному Господу
knows maybe it's written on some other
известно возможно ещё на каком-нибудь
site but we have enough information that
сайте написано но нам хватит информации
shd looks like this that's
о том что щд выглядит вот
why  we will write down two meanings
так поэтому щед мы запишем два значения
barn and spill Although no Let's even
сарай и проливать Хотя нет Давайте даже
make an expression shad Light on shed
выражение сделаем shad Light on пролить
light on and write down Old shad old
свет на и запишем ещё Old shad старый
barn
сарай
already before me typing old
уже до меня вбива старый
barn we have here about the accent she is
сарай у нас здесь про акцент она его
apparently trying to hide it in the
пытается видимо спрятать в
barn which they tried so
сарае который пытались так
desperately to hide in the barn so
отча спрятать в сарае так
I did not enter anything
вот я ничего не вводил
additional people of West Virginia
дополнительного люди Западной Вирджинии
and here we see the following
и вот мы видим следующие
pictures of people of West Virginia Well that is such a
картины людей Западной Вирджинии Ну то
pure West Virginia
вот чистая Западная Вирджиния
what your father does
чем твой отец
he is a coal
занимается он угольный
miner this is
Шахтёр это
coal this is to mine coal
уголь это добывать уголь как
just the one who mines coal
раз тот кто добывает уголь
Miner of mines or coal miner they even
Шахтёр шахт или угольщик ещ даже
offer he mines you have
предлагают он шахт у тебя
M A well yes they They do
М А ну да они Они же
exist Let's
бывают Давайте
write here is a lamp from the mine Yes such a
напишем вот лампа из Шахты Да такая
kerosene one It
керосиновая
smells of a lamp of kerosene More precisely it
От него воняет лампой керосином Точнее
smells of kerosene Yes that one
керосином от него воняет Да вот тот
which is in the
который в
lamp I listened to
лампе ещ раз переслушал
AG Darling you again Think you can me with
AG Darling you Think you can me with
BL
BL
no I thought that knowledge so ambitious AR you you
no I thought that knowledge so ambitious
know  What you look like to me
AR you you know What you look like to me
with your Good Bag and your Shoes you
with your Good Bag and your Shoes you
look like a
look like a
redling with Little T
redling with Little
Nutrition Some length of B But not
T Nutrition Some length of B But not
more One Generation Po
More One Generation Po
triper
triper
West You Know How quickly the Boys found
West You Know How quickly the Boys found
you All those sticky FS The Back seats
you All those sticky FS The Back seats
of Cars while you could Only Dream of
of Cars while you could Only Dream of
getting Out getting any getting all the
getting Out getting any getting all the
way to the
way to the
And how
И как же
quickly the boys found
быстро мальчики нашли
you all e
тебя все
Let's take it in
э Давайте нанм по
order tedious boring tedious Well,
порядку утомительный скучный нудный нука
and the pictures Well, here we see Wherever
а картинки Ну вот мы видим Везде где
boredom drives people crazy Just
людей с ума скука сводит просто
all those boring boring
все эти скучные нудные
Yes, that's the one to whom something sticks sticky
Да это тот которому что-то липнет липкие
Well, that's what he calls them, these Bo
Ну то есть он их так называет этих Bo
boys, these boring sticky
мальчиков эти скучные
Clumsy awkward but since
липкие Неуклюжий неловкий но так как у
we have them,
нас
they are bunglers in this
они то это растяпы в этом
ki
ки
rast in the back seats of
раст на задних сидениях
cars [music] while you could only
машин пока ты могла лишь
dream of ch  to get
мечтать чтобы
out to get somewhere
выбраться попасть хоть куда-нибудь
[music]
[музыка]
go all the
пройти весь
way VB so once again
путь ВБ так ещё раз
[music]
[музыка]
see a
see a
lot are you Strong Enough to High Power perception Yourself
lot are you Strong Enough
What Why Don't You Why Don't You Look
Yourself What Why Don't You Why Don't
at Yourself Down
You Look at Yourself Down
you
you
[music]
[музыка]
Maybe see lot see a lot
Maybe see lot see a lot
you see a lot
вы видите многое
Doctor but are you strong enough
Доктор но вы достаточно сильны
to point
ли чтобы направить
that power
это сила
power high-powered
мощность высокомощный
[music] once again
[музыка]
But are you Strong Enough but
ещё раз But are you Strong Enough но
are you strong enough to Point
достаточно ли вы сильны to Point чтобы
that High powered perception
направить that High powered perception
this is high-powered the word perception let's
это высокомощный слово perception
look at
отдельно посмотрим
perception separately here he used the word thrill in relation to her me with your
perception вот он в отношении к ней
Surprise me with your insight here is the
Удивите меня своей проницательностью вот
word perception something similar to AC he
слово perception что-то похожее на AC он
gave her the word AC she gave him perception
ей отвесил слово AC она ему perception
insight perception
проницательность
sensations Awareness etc. etc.
восприятие ощущения Осознание и тд и тп
Let's write down perception
Давайте запишем именно восприятие потому
because more often in this
что чаще в этом
meaning the perception of the world from the point of view of
значение восприятие мира с точки зрения
children Yes children's
детей Да детское
perception the feeling of
восприятие ощущение
depth human perception spe
глубины человеческое восприятие spe
perception of
восприятие
speech vos
речи вос
in the
во
Bible demonstrates unusual
Библии демонстрирует необычное
perception for a boy his
восприятие для мальчика его
age calls
возраста называет
him
его
high on himself how to direct him to us
высоком на себя как нас его направить
m why don't you look at
м почему бы вам не посмотреть на самого
yourself and write down what you
себя и не записать что вы
see or
видите или может
maybe you're afraid to do so so
быть вы боитесь сделать
again
так так ещ раз
Strong High Power perception Yourself
Strong High Power perception Yourself
[music]
[музыка]
that same
та самая
scene census suddenly Yes where else would we
сцена перепись внезапно Да где бы мы ещё
meet the word population census
встретили слово перепись населения
literally
буквально
for what there is such a
за что есть такой
person once tried to test
человек как-то пытался протестировать
me I ate his
меня Я съел его
liver some amount of bobo
печень каким-то количеством бобо
with good poemu
с хорошим поему
Wine - this wine is written by the way that's exactly how it should have been
Вино - это вино пишется кстати вот так
read
именно по сути должно было читаться
but what
но его
with a good bottle
че с хорошей бутылочкой
test check
протестировать проверить
fly back to
лети назад в
school little
школу маленькая
Stalin fly fly fly
Сталин лети лети
so now I'll give you everything again to
лети так сейчас я вам дам заново всё
review before that I'll remind you That
пересмотреть до этого напомню Что у нас
today we have as many as 29 cards that you can
сегодня аж 29 карточек которые вы можете
download from the link in the description of this
скачать по ссылке в описании к этому
video I'll add pictures to each
видео я добавлю картинки к каждой
card you can practice there will
карточке можно будет попрактиковаться
also be exercises because in
также будут упражнения потому что в
quizlet there are only cards and not much
квизлет только карточки и не так много
free functionality But in wordwall
функционала бесплатного А вот в wordwall
it's shorter There will be more exercises Where
это короче Будут ещё упражнения Где
you can in any mode there in the game not in the
можно в любом режиме там игровом не
game all this is also with the same
игровом всё это тоже с такими же точно
cards to work listen to
карточками поработать послушать
study and there will also be of course a
позаниматься и также будет конечно же
working  a notebook with exercises so
рабочая тетрадь с упражнениями для того
that you can
чтобы всю сегодняшнюю лексику вы могли
learn and work through all of today's vocabulary and the text of
выучить и проработать и текст
today's video will also be in
сегодняшнего ролика тоже будет в полном
full you can also download this entire dialogue
объёме весь этот диалог Вы тоже можете
and work through it in text form
скачать и позаниматься в текстовом виде
for today's lesson Now let's
по сегодняшнему уроку А теперь давайте
review everything again
пересмотри всё заново
[music]
[музыка]
my
my
name I am Yes May ials closer please closer that expires in One We F Training Jack craw Train May can sit
name I am
Please
Please
What you MS in
What you MS in
Next you What
Next you What
say smell I
say
Myself
smell I Myself
cannot you use Skin Cream And you didn't do
cannot you use Skin
All
not did All
aging I have
aging I have
inad per
inad
US No you doing F
US No you doing F
seg won do I'm Only Asking you to Look
seg won do I'm Only Asking you to Look
at this Doctor either You will you won
at this Doctor either You will you won
Yeah Jack must be very busy indeed If he
Yeah Jack must be very busy indeed If he
is recruiting Help from the Student Body
is recruiting Help from the Student Body
busy hunting that New Buffalo B What a
busy hunting that New Buffalo B What a
Naughty Boy he
Naughty Boy
You Know Why he called Buffalo Bill
he You Know Why he called Buffalo Bill
Please tell me
Please tell me
lik Why do you think remes skop
lik Why do you think remes skop
you S that trun
you S that trun
aging you Think you can BL
aging you Think you can
So You know you like your Good
So You know you like your Good
[music]
[музыка]
shes more
shes more
Know How Quick the Boys you
Know How Quick the Boys you
those back Car you could Dream
those back Car you could Dream
Out All
Out All
Strong Power
Strong Power
[music]
[музыка]
Thank you very much for watching With you
Спасибо вам большое за просмотр С вами
was this English see you in the
был вот это английский увидимся в
next episode Don't forget
следующем выпуске Не забудьте
to subscribe If you haven't subscribed to the
подписаться Если ещё не подписаны на
channel yet Bye
канал Пока